<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: guide, | Duke PL Course]]></title>
  <link href="http://Duke-PL-Course.github.com/blog/categories/guide-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Duke-PL-Course.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-17T15:04:08-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://Duke-PL-Course.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Yang Su, Kevin Gao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Installing and Configuring Vim]]></title>
    <link href="http://Duke-PL-Course.github.com/blog/2013/01/17/configuring-vim/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-17T15:55:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Duke-PL-Course.github.com/blog/2013/01/17/configuring-vim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="toc_17">Installing Vim</h2>

<p>Most Unix-like systems like Mac OS X or Linux distributions will come with Vim installed already. However, you may want to upgrade vim for better compatibility or new features. Here, we will cover some of the recommended ways to install <code>vim</code>.</p>

<p><em>TL;DR: Here is a link to the <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/bka5j2rkobq0gxu/vimdotfiles.tgz">vim dotfiles</a> recommended for a base configuration.</em></p>

<h3 id="toc_18">OS X Installation</h3>

<p>One option to install Vim for OS X is to use <a href="http://code.google.com/p/macvim/">MacVim</a>, a GUI version of vim. Simply download and install MacVim from its project page&#39;s <a href="http://code.google.com/p/macvim/downloads/list">Downloads</a> tab. Installation just requires unarchiving the <code>.tbz</code> file (Archive Utility should be able to do this for you by double clicking on the archive). Finally, drag and drop the <code>MacVim.app</code> bundle into your <code>/Applications/</code> folder.</p>

<p>Alternatively, you can use <a href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/"><code>brew</code></a> to install MacVim. If you prefer a terminal-based vim, than you can run the following commands with <code>brew</code>:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="bash">brew install vim --with-python --with-ruby --with-perl --with-lua --with-tcl
</code></pre>
</div>

<h3 id="toc_19">Windows Installation</h3>

<p>You can download the latest version of vim directly from the <a href="http://www.vim.org/download.php#pc">vim webpage</a>. This includes the binaries for the 32-bit and 64-bit version of Windows.</p>

<p>Alternatively, you can install a command-line version of vim through <a href="http://www.cygwin.com/">Cygwin</a>, a Unix-like environment and CLI for Windows. First <a href="http://cygwin.com/install.html">install Cygwin</a> by downloading the <code>setup.exe</code> file. Run the <code>setup.exe</code> file with your preferred installation settings. Once reaching the &quot;Select Packages&quot; screen, scroll down to the <strong>Editors</strong> node and expand it. Finally, find <strong>vim</strong> in the list and change the <em>Skip</em> option to <em>Install</em>. Next, just finish the install ation.</p>

<h2 id="toc_20">Linux Installation</h2>

<p>To install or upgrade <code>vim</code> on a Linux distribution, use the package manager of your choice (e.g. <code>apt</code>, <code>yum</code>, <code>pacman</code>, etc.). Typically the command will look something like:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="bash">sudo apt-get install vim gvim <span class="c"># gvim is optional</span>
</code></pre>
</div>

<h2 id="toc_21">Configuring Vim</h2>

<p>By default, the start of your vim configuration is found in <code>$HOME/.vimrc</code>; additional plugins, settings, etc. are found in <code>$HOME/.vim</code>. On Windows, <code>$HOME</code> is going to be <code>%userprofile%</code>, so something akin to <code>C:\Users\Your Name\</code>, and the <code>.vim</code> folder will be called <code>vimfiles</code>. This is due to the fact that NTFS directories are not supposed to start with periods.</p>

<p>We have compiled a base <code>.vimrc</code> file and relevant plugins. You can download these settings files <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/bka5j2rkobq0gxu/vimdotfiles.tgz">here</a>. Simply place them in your $HOME directory as described above. <strong>NOTE: If you already use vim and have existing dot files, you will have to manually merge the .vimrc</strong>.</p>

<p>This configuration uses <a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-pathogen">Pathogen</a> to load bundled plugins, so you should be able to integrate this with any existing plugins relatively easily.</p>

<h2 id="toc_22">Congratulations</h2>

<p>If you&#39;ve reached this point, you&#39;ve now successfully installed and configured Vim. It should look something like this:</p>

<p><img src="/images/vim_done.png" alt="Configured Vim"><br>
<em>Note: The NERDTree plugin has been opened by issuing :NERDTreeToggle</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up Sublime Text 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://Duke-PL-Course.github.com/blog/2013/01/15/setting-up-sublime-text-2/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-15T02:44:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Duke-PL-Course.github.com/blog/2013/01/15/setting-up-sublime-text-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="toc_23">Intro</h2>

<p><img src="/images/st2.jpg" alt="Sublime Text 2 Logo"></p>

<p>Sublime Text 2 is an incredibly fast and powerful editor that&#39;s been replacing <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vim_(text_editor">vim</a>), <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emacs">emacs</a>, and <a href="http://macromates.com/">textmate</a> for many. The community and ecosystem is passionate and vibrant, with developers writing packages for nearly everything. It&#39;s also freely available for all three major platforms, which makes it ideal for this class. You can download Sublime Text 2 from its <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/">website</a>.</p>

<h2 id="toc_24">Package Control</h2>

<p>Sublime Text 2 supports Textmate Snippets, Syntax Highlighting, and other packages that made Textmate successful. However, Sublime Text 2 did not include a package manager out of the box. Developer <a href="http://wbond.net/">@wbond</a> has created <a href="http://wbond.net/sublime_packages/package_control">a full-featured package manager</a> that helps discovering, installing, updating and removing packages for Sublime Text 2.</p>

<p>To install <a href="http://wbond.net/sublime_packages/package_control">Package Control</a>, open up Sublime Text 2, and hit <code>ctrl+&#39;</code> or click on <strong><em>View &gt; Show Console</em></strong> to open up the Console. Once open, paste in the following command:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="python"><span class="kn">import</span> <span class="nn">urllib2</span><span class="o">,</span><span class="nn">os</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="n">pf</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s">&#39;Package Control.sublime-package&#39;</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="n">ipp</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">sublime</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">installed_packages_path</span><span class="p">();</span> <span class="n">os</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">makedirs</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">ipp</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="k">if</span> <span class="ow">not</span> <span class="n">os</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">path</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">exists</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">ipp</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="k">else</span> <span class="bp">None</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="n">urllib2</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">install_opener</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">urllib2</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">build_opener</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">urllib2</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">ProxyHandler</span><span class="p">()));</span> <span class="nb">open</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">os</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">path</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">join</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">ipp</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">pf</span><span class="p">),</span><span class="s">&#39;wb&#39;</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">write</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">urllib2</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">urlopen</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">&#39;http://sublime.wbond.net/&#39;</span><span class="o">+</span><span class="n">pf</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">replace</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">&#39; &#39;</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="s">&#39;%20&#39;</span><span class="p">))</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">read</span><span class="p">());</span> <span class="k">print</span> <span class="s">&#39;Please restart Sublime Text to finish installation&#39;</span>
</code></pre>
</div>

<p><img src="/images/console.png" alt="Console"><br>
<em>Note: ignore the text displayed in the console shown above.</em></p>

<p>Press enter to execute the code. Sublime text should display the message </p>

<p><blockquote><p><br><br/>Please restart Sublime Text to finish installation<br></p></blockquote></p>

<p>After restarting Sublime Text 2, you should be able to use Package Control. For more detailed instructions on installation, see the <a href="http://wbond.net/sublime_packages/package_control/installation">Package Control Installation Guide</a>.</p>

<p>You can access all the Package Control Commands with Sublime Text&#39;s Command Palette, which you can bring up with <code>Control+Shift+P</code> or <code>Command+Shift+P</code> on Mac.</p>

<p><img src="/images/command-palette.png" alt="Command Palette"></p>

<p>A detailed description of each command can be found <a href="http://wbond.net/sublime_packages/package_control/usage">here</a>.</p>

<h2 id="toc_25">Packages</h2>

<p>Sublime Text natively supports JavaScript, Ruby, Scala, Erlang, Clojure, and Haskell.</p>

<h3 id="toc_26">Prolog</h3>

<p>For Prolog, a syntax highlighting package has been created by <a href="https://github.com/alnkpa/sublimeprolog">@alnkpa</a>. It can be installed by using <em>Install Package</em> from the <em>Command Palette</em>, which will bring up a separate window that lists all the available packages after a few seconds. Type in <em>Prolog</em> in the search and you should be able to see the package after a few key strokes. Select the <em>Prolog</em> package and press enter to install. Then that&#39;s it. </p>

<p>Sublime Text will recognize files that with the extensions <code>pl</code> or <code>pro</code> as Prolog source files. However, <code>pl</code> is commonly used as an extension for Perl and Sublime Text will select Perl as in the language instead of Prolog if you use a <code>pl</code> extension. As a result, we prefer to use <code>pro</code>.</p>

<p><img src="/images/prolog-package.png" alt="Prolog Package"></p>

<p>As a side note, you can set the syntax of any source file at any time by using <em>Command Palette</em> &gt; <em>Set Syntax: (Language)</em> to set the syntax of the current file to the language of your choice.</p>

<h3 id="toc_27">Io</h3>

<p>A package for Io has actually been created by one of the instructors <a href="https://github.com/yangsu/sublime-io">@yangsu</a>. Used <em>Install Package</em> to install a package called <em>Io Langugae</em>.</p>

<p>After the installation completes, Sublime Text will recognize any file with <code>io</code> extension as <code>io</code> source files. As noted above, you can also set the syntax of any source file to io with <em>Command Palette</em> &gt; <em>Set Syntax: (Language)</em>.</p>

<h3 id="toc_28">Additional Resources</h3>

<p><a href="https://tutsplus.com/">Tuts+</a> is an amazing collection of resources for almost everything related to technical or design knowledge. It&#39;s highly recommended for anyone trying to learn anything from Photoshop to <a href="http://nodejs.org/">Node.js</a>. <a href="https://tutsplus.com/">Tuts+</a> also has a whole network of sites with focuses in particular areas. Scroll to the bottom of the <a href="https://tutsplus.com/">Tuts+ page</a>, and you will be able to see all the available options.</p>

<p><a href="http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/">NetTuts+</a> in particular has many great tutorials on Sublime Text. Two of the best articles are <a href="http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/tools-and-tips/sublime-text-2-tips-and-tricks/">Sublime Text 2 Tips and Tricks</a> and <a href="http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/tools-and-tips/essential-sublime-text-2-plugins-and-extensions/">Essential Sublime Text 2 Plugins and Extensions</a>.</p>

<p>You can also follow <a href="https://tutsplus.com/course/improve-workflow-in-sublime-text-2/">a free video series</a> by Jeffrey Way on <a href="https://tutsplus.com/">Tuts+</a> that goes over many of the topics covered in the two articles above and more.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
